# Anthony Hien Vu

Full Stack Web Developer | Tech Lead

## Contact

### **Address**

Wentworthville, NSW, 2145

### **Phone**

0452668725

#### **Email**

avu120@gmail.com

### **Portfolio**

https://avu120.github.io/por folio

### **GitHub**

https://aithub.com/AVu120

### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/ir/anthony-hien-vu/

### **Skills**

React

Excellen<sup>a</sup>

Redux

Excellent

CSS/Modules/SASS/CSS-in-JS/CSS-in-HTML

Excellent

Full Stack Web Developer (with a strong preference for the frontend) and Tech Lead. I have also worked in DevOps (I have 2 AWS associate certifications & experience building CICD pipelines). I've also worked in QA (including writing automated end to end and API tests).

# **Work History**

2021-09 – now

# Senior Full Stack Web Developer | Tech Lead

Checkbox, Sydney, NSW

- Architected full-stack technical design for new features and user workflows.
- Built new React UI with Redux in the primary B2B application.
- Built new and modified existing Go (Golang) APIs.
- Implemented automated end to end and API tests (in CypressJS).
- Implemented migration from JavaScript to TypeScript on the frontend.
- Implemented mass-adoption of unit/integration tests on the frontend with Jest and React Testing Library.
- Trained/mentored junior engineers in React/frontend best practices (in areas like performance optimization and testing).
- Implemented agile team processes to reduce process ambiguity and improve consistency of team output.
- Influenced future product feature roadmap and technical architecture decisions.
- Added many new and old UI components to the Storybook.js design system.

2021-03 -2021-09

# Full Stack Web Developer

oOh!media, Sydney, NSW

- Built new features into internal React & Redux applications.
- Gave comprehensive React training to mid & seniorlevel engineers.
- Built evergreen internal UI design system using Storybook.js.

React Testing Excellent Accessibility / WCAG Automated End2End Testing Web Sockets Very Good Storybook (UI Design Excellent Figma (Design/Wireframe Node/Express Excellent **AWS** Very Good **Building REST APIs** Excellent **Building GraphQL APIs** Good **SQL** Databases Very Good

NoSQL Databases

Very Good

- Built new features in Node Express.js/GraphQL servers.
- Built new features in python API servers.
- Made configuration changes in AWS services like SQS, Lambda and EC2.
- Made configuration changes to Concourse CICD pipelines.

# 2018-08 - Full Stack Web Developer

2021-02

Telstra, Sydney, NSW

- Performed full stack development of a Telstra enterprise web application with thousands of internal users utilizing the MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) stack with redux. The primary feature of this application is a catalogue of charts displaying data from various sources. I built new features into this application every day. Some examples include allowing the users to query databases from within the application, automatically schedule user-written scripts against databases, set up monitoring & alarms, and many more. The application uses a microservices architecture and is deployed on AWS.
- Troubleshooted operational issues in AWS core services such as CloudWatch, EC2, ECR and DocumentDB.
- Containerized many applications using Docker.
- Configured NGINX reverse-proxies to forward requests to various servers/micro-services-in-dockercontainers.
- Wrote unit tests using Jest.js, Enzyme.js and React Testing Library.
- Set up CICD pipelines using Atlassian's Bamboo platform.
- Documented many APIs using Swagger/OpenAPI specification.

2017-02 - **IT Consultant** 

KPMG, Sydney, NSW

VueJS	
	Good
Angular	
	Good
	0000
Languages	
JavaScript	
	Excellent
TypeScript	
	Evaallant
	Excellent
Python	Excellent
Python	Excellent  Very Good
Python Go (Golang)	
	Very Good
Go (Golang)	Very Good
Go (Golang)	Very Good Very Good
Go (Golang) Java	Very Good Very Good

### Education

2013-02 -2016-11

# **Bachelor of Science: Engineering**

Sydney University - Sydney, NSW

# **Certifications**

2021-07

**AWS Certified Solutions Architect - Associate** 

2021-03

**AWS Certified Developer - Associate** 

### **Interests**

- Improving developer experience (I'm quite proactive on updating documentation and innovating with new team processes)
- Mentoring
- Leadership
- System architecture
- Web app performance
- UX Design
- Accessibility
- DevOps/Cloud/Serverless
- Al/Machine-Learning
- Staying up to date with the latest technologies, trends, and best practices.

# **Hobbies**

- Ice Skating
- Cricket
- Hiking
- Running
- Reading
- Tech Meetups
- Traveling